Darin Bolton

E-mail DarinRBolton1@gmail.com

Address 808 County Road 1517

Phone 903-422-4985

Jacksonville, Texas

Soon-to-be college graduate with 1+ years of experience working with Amazon Web Services and Red Hat Linux. Outgoing and detail-oriented, I am proficient at building and maintaining professional relationships. I will soon have an Associates of Applied Science (AAS) degree in Cloud and Data Center Management.

Education

2016-12 - 2019-04	Texas State Technical College (TSTC) • Associates of Applied Science - Cloud and Data Center Management
2011-08 - 2014-06	Jacksonville High School • High School Diploma

Certificates

Chille	
2012-04	Adobe Certified Associate - Adobe Dreamweaver CS5
2012-05	Adobe Certified Associate - Adobe Flash CS5
2013-02	Adobe Certified Associate - Adobe Photoshop CS5
2014-05	IC3 Digital Literacy
2018-04	AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate

Skills

Advanced knowledge of **Amazon Web Services** (S3 Object Storage, EC2, Route 53, AWS Databases, VPC, AWS Application Services)

Intermediate knowledge of Microsoft Azure and Docker

Strong understanding of **Red Hat Linux** (package management, file systems, networking, controlling file access, SELinux, adding users and groups, managing processes)

Experienced with Windows Server 2012 (Active Directory, Hyper-V, IP address management, data backups)

Expert knowledge of entire Microsoft Office suite (Word, Excel, PowerPoint)

Proficient in scripting with Windows Powershell

Basic understanding of C++ and Python programming language

Experienced in managing **SQL** databases

Excellent selling and communicative skills

Courses

2018-01 - 2018-04	Cloud Deployment and Infrastructure
2018-04 - 2018-08	Administering SQL Server
2017-04 - 2017-08	Advanced Linux Installation and Configuration

Experience

2018-12 - 2019-01 **Junior Cloud Engineer**

HumannHart Solutions LLC

Assisted in lift and shift app migration into Microsoft Azure for over 32 applications, resulting in a projected savings of \$11,000 per month. Gained experience using Docker, Azure, and CentOS.

2019-01 - present Verizon Click-to-Chat Sales

Etech Global Services LLC

Responsible for identifying the needs and requirements for current and potential Verizon Wireless customers, answering any inquiries the customer may have, and responding to multiple customers simultaneously through an online chat client. Also responsible for driving sales, placing orders, and ensuring the customer has a pleasant

online chatting experience.

2018-11 - 2019-01 Computer Sales Associate

Best Buy, Computer Department, Seasonal

Identified the needs and requirements of the customer, organized sales pitches, and prioritized completing the sale while maximizing revenue. Exemplified knowledge of products and services offered within the store while maintaining a strong customer service orientation. Other tasks included maintaining product availability, securing product with appropriate anti-theft devices, and frequent use of a point-of-sale system.

2013-05 - 2015-05 **Head Lifeguard**

City of Jacksonville

Provided aquatic safety to swimming patrons, basic swimming pool maintenance, CPR and First Aid certified, tendered cash transactions and answered phone calls in a professional demeanor. Responsible for ensuring other lifeguards completed their duties, identified problems and dealt with them professionally, and held to a higher level of general responsibility.

2014-12 - 2015-03 **Assembly Line**

Federal Heath

Built and assembled large aluminum and steel commercial signs using air-powered tools. Responsible for assembling signs in a timely manner, transporting them, and assisting in loading signs for shipment.

References

Trystan Humann, HumannHart Solutions LLC

Phone: 423-307-7906

Email: TrystanHumann@gmail.com

Brad Golemon, Infrastructure Architect, Santander Consumer USA Inc.

Phone: 214-886-8037